The hands will never surpass the eyes.
Unless you cultivate the "eyes"
to discern good from bad,
Class Check
~Production~
Correct Answer Waiting Room
you cannot hope to improve the
"hands" that create works of art.
It's a phrase that's often
used among creators,
but it applies to all kinds of fields.
Those with good "eyes" will improve
far more rapidly than those without!
When I throw my right horizontal punch,
he immediately sends a left vertical jab!
Itadori wasn't moving like that before!
He's improving...
by devouring me!
What a beautiful way to knock me down!
His face is wide open!
I can hit it!
Even with Divergent Fist!
However!
He stopped my fist with his forehead
before it could reach full speed?!
That's not what I want you
to devour right now.
Your Divergent Fist
is created by your cursed energy
lagging behind your
superhuman physical prowess,
when normally it would never lag.
It's a tricky move.
Your average sorcerer wouldn't know what
happened, and they'd be left disoriented.
It carries plenty of force, too.
For opponents on that level, at least!
But it won't work against special-grades.
What will you do, best friend?
Imbue my full strength with
cursed energy at the right moment.
Good!
So then why is your cursed energy lagging?
It's because you're channeling it!
Huh?
Wait, I thought we were talking
about channeling it faster...
We channel cursed energy.
Many sorcerers do this consciously.
"My stomach's full of rage."
"The blood's boiling in my gut."
The theory is that cursed energy extracted
from such negative emotions
Curse
starts in the navel and is
channeled throughout the body.
They say it flows from the navel to the chest,
then the shoulders, arms,
and finally the fists,
but this perception of
the body as individual parts
is what delays cursed energy.
The idea of channeling cursed
energy isn't wrong in itself.
But that's only the first step!
You can't let yourself remain
too trapped by that concept.
The better the sorcerer, the harder it is
to read the flow of their cursed energy.
For a different reason from why yours is.
Do we think with our guts?
Do we express anger with our heads?
Listen to me, Itadori.
We exist in this world with our entire mind,
body, and soul as one whole.
It's such a given that
everyone forgets about it.
Thanks, Toudou.
I think I get it now.
Then no more words are needed.
I won't hold back.
I'll guide you with my full strength!
Don't die on me, Itadori!
Rise up to greater heights!
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Episode 16: Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event - Group Battle 2 -
Hey, you.
Your old fart told you to kill Itadori, right?
This girl has good intuition.
No, that was probably Panda-chan.
Huh? What do you mean?
You really don't need to hide it.
I'm out to kill someone, too.
Especially that bitch Mai,
the watered-down version of Maki.
What?
Don't "What?" me.
Even Pepper-kun gives slightly
better responses than that.
What, she's not getting mad?
But I feel the same way right now!
Oh, I almost forgot. You guys
have your own Pepper-kun, huh?
Maybe I'll scrap it and dump it somewhere.
Scary...
Panda-senpai!
It's a cursed corpse.
It won't die.
Though it won't be able to move for a while.
Now, who were you calling a Pepper-kun?
Hold on, Mechamaru.
I'll beat this first-year into cute shape.
I'll show her how Mai-chan's suffered
and teach her all about what it means
for a woman to live as a jujutsu sorcerer.
Just kidding.
Huh?
You looking for attention?
You should focus on support
and staying hidden.
Well, let's just get along,
since we're so similar.
Damn puppet...
What do you know?!
Good grief. What happened
to hunting cursed spirits?
Sword Option:
Boost On!
Ultra Spin!
Can't you keep still?
I need to finish this quickly.
I'd rather leave him be and go
help Nobara, but he fires at range.
We didn't have information on
Mechamaru, Nishimiya, or Miwa, but...
You're strong.
What grade are you?
First-Grade
Semi-
Second-Grade
Third-Grade
By my guess, this is where everyone stands.
It's a little too much
for Nobara to handle.
I don't think my rating against
cursed spirits is needed right now,
but I'll tell you.
Semi-first-grade.
Huh?
Ultra Cannon!
His area of attack is huge!
Heat emission!
It's a technique with big
build-up and cool-down.
This output is pointless if
I don't hit its core dead-on.
Cursed corpses.
That's the generic name
for inanimate objects
that house curses and can
operate independently.
Man-made cursed corpses always have
a core that serves as their heart.
Panda is the ultimate masterpiece
by myself, Yaga Masamichi,
the leading expert on
puppeteering cursed techniques.
He's a cursed corpse born with emotions...
A cursed corpse mutation!
Panda... is not a panda!
I can't follow his movements!
I guess if there was another like me,
I would have at least heard rumors.
The fact that I haven't
means you're not a cursed corpse.
You're a sorcerer who's remote-controlling
this thing while your main body's elsewhere.
That doesn't mean you should snap over
being treated like a cursed corpse.
You don't like being similar to me?
You wound me.
I think it actually hurts!
Judging from your cursed energy output,
your main body shouldn't be that far away.
No, you're just outside the arena, huh?
Guess there's no point in
hunting you down, then.
You'd just be free to act in the meantime.
So I guess I'll just bust you up.
You won't be doing either.
Heavenly pact.
Have you heard of it?
It's not like a pact normally
forged with oneself.
It's a pact forced upon the body
from the moment it's born.
I was born without a right arm
or anything below my knees,
and I had no sensation from the waist down.
My skin is so fragile that
even moonlight burns it,
and it constantly feels like needles
are stabbing every pore of my body.
But in exchange, I've been granted the ability
to use cursed techniques over vast distances,
as well as immense cursed energy production.
I didn't ask for any of this power.
If I could trade my cursed techniques
to have a normal body, I'd gladly do so.
So when I see a cursed corpse like you
walking around in broad daylight
without a care instead of me,
I just cannot stand it!
Ultimate Mechamaru,
Mode: Albatross!
That's an incredible
amount of cursed energy!
And given his position,
Nobara's in his line of fire!
I have to block it!
Ultimate Cannon!
It's dead?
No, the very concept of death
doesn't apply to you.
You revealed your technique
while boasting about your misfortune, then.
Quite the sorcerer thing to do.
It's still alive after taking a hit
from Ultimate Cannon?!
I'm kind of pissed now.
What is that form?
Panda... is not a panda!
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Panda.
You have an older brother
and an older sister.
No, I do not.
Yes, you do.
They're inside you.
And why the polite tone?
Inside me?
Yes. You'll understand someday.
Those two will always,
always lend you strength.
Sword Option: Ultra Shield!
Normally, a cursed corpse has
a single core for its heart.
But there are three cores inside me,
and by switching out which one is
the main core, I can convert my body.
There's the Panda core, focused on balance...
my older brother, Gorilla Core,
focused on power for short, decisive battles...
and my bashful older sister.
His first attack got my older sister's core,
and that last one exhausted the Panda core.
I have no choice left but to
beat him with Gorilla Mode!
He doesn't pack as much power as Toudou.
But that palm strike just now
went all the way to my internals.
Even if I guard, I'll still take damage.
You realized it?
This is Gorilla Mode's special move,
the unstoppable Drumming Beat!
If I take that Drumming Beat
to my head or chest,
I won't be able to move Mechamaru anymore.
My right arm, Sword Option,
is no longer functioning.
I can't fire Ultimate Cannon anymore, either.
Gorilla Mode pounds through
cursed energy like a gorilla.
I need to hurry.
I crushed his right arm.
He can't fire off his
ultimate attack anymore.
No swords in his left or his mouth,
so only ranged blasts left?
Even so, he shouldn't fire them haphazardly.
Mechamaru believes he failed to finish
me with those blasts twice already,
despite actually putting two
of my cores close to death.
This time he'll likely blast my core
with point-blank precision
or try to finish me with a slash.
However...
I have the advantage at close range!
A tile?
Did he pick it off the roof just now?
A distraction, then jet acceleration!
He's experienced at this!
This time, I won't miss!
Its core is where its
cursed energy is densest!
Right here!
You did well, for a puppet.
Don't treat me like other cursed corpses.
I know how to bluff the position of my core
with cursed energy manipulation.
I'm already concealing the
number of cores, anyway.
You lost because you
underestimated puppets.
I haven't had a single thing in common with
anyone around me from the moment I was born.
I thought you and I could
understand each other in that sense.
Though I've never once
been jealous of humans.
What?
I mean, humans are creepy, you know?
They'll risk their lives and fight
hard toward their goals,
then they'll be laid-back or
wishy-washy. I don't get it.
Still, I do love those aspects
that I don't have,
creepy as they are.
I'm sure you have your own
hardships, too, Mechamaru.
But having more hardships
doesn't make you right.
I mean, it's not like we're
enemies in the first place.
Why are you a jujutsu
sorcerer to begin with?
Because that's the only thing you can do?
I mean, not that it really matters.
But if you want to make something happen,
I'll help you.
Mechamaru.
Don't waste your powerful moves.
You never know when you'll be facing
more than the single enemy before you.
Mechamaru,
don't go thinking someone who can't
instantly state his type of woman
can become a full-fledged jujutsu sorcerer.
Mechamaru, it's just obligatory,
but I got you these instead of chocolates.
I heard you liked AA Evoltas.
I'm not like that.
Huh?
But Mai said—
One day...
together with everyone...
Hm? Say that again?
I wonder if you'll still say you'll
help me after seeing what I look like.
You think I'm going to
fuss over what you look like?
I'm a panda.
Later.
Let me pay you a visit next time.
Shut up, you damn puppet.
I forgot!
Lend me your phone.
Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event Group Battle
Ultimate Mechamaru - Retired
No way!
This woman... is incredibly strong!
Juju Stroll
Mechamaru, let Noritoshi know
Utahime-sensei's calling for him.
Mechamaru, give this to Toudou-kun.
Mechamaru! Perfect timing.
This is for Toudou-senpai and Kamo-senpai.
Why do you all always go through me?
Grk!
Don't talk to me right now.
Takada-chan's live-streaming.
Ibaragi?
It's Ibaraki.
You don't even know that?
Because they're too much trouble, obviously.
I'm honestly still scared of them...
But if I said that, I might not
be able to ask him anymore.
Mechamaru!
We're counting on you!
Time for our missions!
Wait...
Why?
Well, I guess it's good
that they can rely on me.
Episode 17:
Kyoto Sister School Exchange Event - Group Battle 3 -